<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lifestyle | Hugo Academic CV Theme</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/lifestyle/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/lifestyle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Lifestyle</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Lifestyle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/lifestyle/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 April 13th - April 20th - Surviving Early Exams and Finding Balance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/%D0%BD%D0%B5%D0%B4%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8F-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/%D0%BD%D0%B5%D0%B4%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8F-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome 👋&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;details class=&#34;print:hidden xl:hidden&#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;text-sm&#34;&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#week-in-review-may-6th---may-12th---surviving-early-exams-and-finding-balance&#34;&gt;Week in Review. May 6th - May 12th - Surviving Early Exams and Finding Balance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;week-in-review-may-6th---may-12th---surviving-early-exams-and-finding-balance&#34;&gt;Week in Review. May 6th - May 12th - Surviving Early Exams and Finding Balance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! It&amp;rsquo;s time for my weekly update, and let me tell you, this past week has been a whirlwind! I&amp;rsquo;m currently pushing hard to complete my exams ahead of schedule, which has resulted in some seriously late nights. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve also made a conscious effort to maintain a semblance of balance amidst the chaos. Here&amp;rsquo;s a glimpse into what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Accomplishments/Highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•  Early Exam Progress: The biggest highlight has definitely been making progress with my early exams. I’ve been consistently staying up until 3 AM each night, cramming and preparing for these assessments. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely challenging, but I’m determined to get through it.
•  Two Exams Down! I successfully completed and passed two exams this week! I&amp;rsquo;m now finished with History of Religions and the Foundations of Military Training. It&amp;rsquo;s a huge weight off my shoulders and a great boost to my motivation.
•  Finding Time for Nature: Despite the crazy workload, I managed to escape for two walks in the park. It was so refreshing to disconnect from the books and enjoy some fresh air and sunshine.
•  Cultural Outing: I also made time to visit a local art exhibition. It was a wonderful opportunity to appreciate some creativity and get my mind off studying, even if just for a few hours.
•  Language Practice Maintained: I&amp;rsquo;ve been diligently practicing both English and German, even with everything else going on. A little bit of language learning each day helps me stay sharp and keeps my mind engaged in something different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Challenges/Setbacks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•  Exhaustion is Real: The constant late nights have definitely taken their toll. I’m feeling quite tired and have struggled to maintain focus at times.
•  Time Management Struggles: Juggling study, relaxation, and language practice has been a real challenge. There&amp;rsquo;s been a constant battle to prioritize and fit everything in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learnings/Insights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•  Prioritization is Key: I’ve learned that prioritizing tasks and focusing on the most important things is crucial for surviving periods of intense workload.
•  Self-Care is Non-Negotiable: Even when I’m busy, I need to make time for activities that help me relax and recharge. Skipping those activities ultimately makes me less productive.
•  Small Wins Keep Me Going: Even small accomplishments, like completing a practice question or learning a new German phrase, contribute to a sense of progress and keep me motivated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goals for Next Week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•  Finish at least one more exam: My goal is to complete at least one more exam and continue making progress towards my early exam completion.
•  Improve Sleep Schedule (Even Slightly): I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to get to bed a little earlier each night, even if it&amp;rsquo;s just by 30 minutes. Every little bit helps!
•  Continue Language Practice: I&amp;rsquo;ll continue dedicating time to both English and German, even if it&amp;rsquo;s just for a short period each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week has been a rollercoaster of studying, exams, and a few moments of respite. It’s been tough, but I’m feeling positive about the progress I&amp;rsquo;m making. Thanks for reading! How do you cope with periods of intense pressure? Share your tips in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 Last week 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/last-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/last-week-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome 👋&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;details class=&#34;print:hidden xl:hidden&#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;text-sm&#34;&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#life-lately-my-week-in-review&#34;&gt;Life Lately: My Week in Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#career&#34;&gt;Career&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#home&#34;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#learning&#34;&gt;Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fun&#34;&gt;Fun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#reading&#34;&gt;Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;life-lately-my-week-in-review&#34;&gt;Life Lately: My Week in Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, time for a quick recap of the week that was. Not too crazy, but definitely had its moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;career&#34;&gt;Career&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was all about job hunting. I spent a lot of time updating my resume, writing cover letters, and scouring LinkedIn and job boards. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a grind, but I finally sent out a bunch of applications, so fingers crossed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home&#34;&gt;Home&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decided to tackle some long-overdue home improvement projects. I finally got around to organizing my closet (it was a disaster zone!), and I even managed to assemble that new bookshelf I bought ages ago. Small victories, but the apartment feels a lot more organized now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning&#34;&gt;Learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to learn a new language, and this week I actually made some progress! I managed to complete a few lessons on Duolingo and even had a short conversation with a native speaker online. Still a long way to go, but it&amp;rsquo;s encouraging to see some improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fun&#34;&gt;Fun&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needed a break from all the serious stuff, so I made sure to schedule some fun time. I went to a concert with a friend (the band was awesome!), and we also had a board game night at my place. It was exactly what I needed to recharge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading&#34;&gt;Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally finished reading that novel I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for ages! It was a bit of a slow burn, but the ending was really satisfying. Now I need to find a new book to dive into. Any recommendations?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 Week in Review. April 5th, 2025 - April 12th, 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/%D0%BF%D0%BE%D1%81%D1%8220.04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/%D0%BF%D0%BE%D1%81%D1%8220.04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome 👋&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;details class=&#34;print:hidden xl:hidden&#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;text-sm&#34;&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-in-review-april-13th-2025---april-20th-2025&#34;&gt;Week in Review. April 13th, 2025 - April 20th, 2025&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! Time for another weekly update. This post summarizes my key activities, learnings, and reflections from the past week (April 13th - April 20th). It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to keep track of progress, identify areas for improvement, and share what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Accomplishments/Highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•  Project Milestone: Successfully completed the initial design phase for the &amp;ldquo;Starlight&amp;rdquo; project. We presented the mockups to the client and received positive feedback. Next steps are to begin development.
•  Learned a New Skill: Spent time learning the basics of Docker. Completed an online course and started experimenting with small projects.
•  Solved a Challenging Bug: Debugged a particularly tricky issue in the &amp;ldquo;Cosmos API&amp;rdquo;. The root cause was a race condition in the database update logic. After thorough analysis and testing, I implemented a locking mechanism to resolve the issue.
•  Improved Efficiency: Streamlined my workflow by implementing &amp;ldquo;Keyboard Maestro&amp;rdquo; macros. Found that it significantly improved my focus and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Challenges/Setbacks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•  Unexpected Delay: Experienced an unexpected delay in receiving feedback from a colleague on the &amp;ldquo;Integration Document&amp;rdquo;. This impacted my schedule for &amp;ldquo;API Testing&amp;rdquo;.
•  Technical Difficulty: Ran into some technical difficulties with &amp;ldquo;Cloud Functions deployment scripts&amp;rdquo;. Spent more time troubleshooting than anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learnings/Insights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•  Importance of Clear Communication: The delay in feedback highlighted the importance of proactively communicating with team members and setting clear expectations by sending a reminder email early in the week, rather than closer to the deadline.
•  The Value of Documentation: Spending time reading the documentation for &amp;ldquo;Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; saved me a significant amount of time in the long run and avoided potentially costly misconfigurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goals for Next Week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•  Begin Development on &amp;ldquo;Starlight&amp;rdquo;: Start implementing the designs for the &amp;ldquo;Starlight&amp;rdquo; project, focusing on the user authentication module.
•  Continue Learning Docker: Deepen my understanding of Docker by building a multi-container application.
•  Reach out to Maria for Feedback: Follow up with Maria to ensure timely feedback on the &amp;ldquo;Integration Document&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was a productive week with its share of challenges and successes. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to tackling next week&amp;rsquo;s goals and continuing to learn and grow. Thanks for reading! What were your highlights from the past week? Share them in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 Last week</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/get-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome 👋&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;details class=&#34;print:hidden xl:hidden&#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;text-sm&#34;&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#study&#34;&gt;Study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#friends&#34;&gt;Friends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#sports&#34;&gt;Sports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tv-shows&#34;&gt;Tv-shows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#something-else&#34;&gt;Something else.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;study&#34;&gt;Study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week wasn&amp;rsquo;t very busy, but I did have to defend my lab works. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t perfect, but I managed to do it. Also, soon there will be a series of tests, and this week I decided to start preparing. It&amp;rsquo;s better to start early, and not study everything on the last night like last time :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friends&#34;&gt;Friends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I do without meeting with friends? Not a single week goes by without it, the previous one is no exception. This week I met with friends several times. We went to a cafe or to someone&amp;rsquo;s home. It was fun and we shot a bunch of funny videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sports&#34;&gt;Sports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This point has slightly sagged this week, but nevertheless, I visited the fitness center. Lately, I have especially liked Pilates, yoga and stretching. Next week I plan to devote more time to sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv-shows&#34;&gt;Tv-shows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I watched new episodes of several series, I won&amp;rsquo;t talk about all of them, although I would like to mention one series. The series &amp;ldquo;Univer. Young&amp;rdquo; was recently released. It&amp;rsquo;s something like a continuation of the old &amp;ldquo;Univer&amp;rdquo;. But in fact, this new season is far from being as funny, and it feels like the writers have forgotten how to joke. It was better before!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;something-else&#34;&gt;Something else.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to pass my exams early, and to do that I need the consent of all the teachers. It turns out that it&amp;rsquo;s quite a quest to find everyone and ask them to sign. I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to do it completely this week, so I&amp;rsquo;ll continue next week. I hope that it won&amp;rsquo;t turn out that my application was written incorrectly!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
