<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | Hugo Academic CV Theme</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 Last week</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/get-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome 👋&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;details class=&#34;print:hidden xl:hidden&#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;text-sm&#34;&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#study&#34;&gt;Study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#friends&#34;&gt;Friends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#sports&#34;&gt;Sports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tv-shows&#34;&gt;Tv-shows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#something-else&#34;&gt;Something else.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;study&#34;&gt;Study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week wasn&amp;rsquo;t very busy, but I did have to defend my lab works. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t perfect, but I managed to do it. Also, soon there will be a series of tests, and this week I decided to start preparing. It&amp;rsquo;s better to start early, and not study everything on the last night like last time :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friends&#34;&gt;Friends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I do without meeting with friends? Not a single week goes by without it, the previous one is no exception. This week I met with friends several times. We went to a cafe or to someone&amp;rsquo;s home. It was fun and we shot a bunch of funny videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sports&#34;&gt;Sports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This point has slightly sagged this week, but nevertheless, I visited the fitness center. Lately, I have especially liked Pilates, yoga and stretching. Next week I plan to devote more time to sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv-shows&#34;&gt;Tv-shows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I watched new episodes of several series, I won&amp;rsquo;t talk about all of them, although I would like to mention one series. The series &amp;ldquo;Univer. Young&amp;rdquo; was recently released. It&amp;rsquo;s something like a continuation of the old &amp;ldquo;Univer&amp;rdquo;. But in fact, this new season is far from being as funny, and it feels like the writers have forgotten how to joke. It was better before!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;something-else&#34;&gt;Something else.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to pass my exams early, and to do that I need the consent of all the teachers. It turns out that it&amp;rsquo;s quite a quest to find everyone and ask them to sign. I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to do it completely this week, so I&amp;rsquo;ll continue next week. I hope that it won&amp;rsquo;t turn out that my application was written incorrectly!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 Version Control &amp; Git. A Quick Overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/get-started-1-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/get-started-1-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome 👋&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;details class=&#34;print:hidden xl:hidden&#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;text-sm&#34;&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#version-control--git-a-quick-overview&#34;&gt;Version Control &amp;amp; Git: A Quick Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#key-git-concepts&#34;&gt;Key Git Concepts:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#basic-git-workflow&#34;&gt;Basic Git Workflow:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#benefits-of-using-git&#34;&gt;Benefits of Using Git:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#where-to-learn-more&#34;&gt;Where to Learn More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;version-control--git-a-quick-overview&#34;&gt;Version Control &amp;amp; Git: A Quick Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control is essential for any software project, no matter how small. Git is a powerful and popular tool for managing your code effectively. Here are a few key takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is Version Control? It&amp;rsquo;s a system that tracks changes to files over time. Think of it like a &amp;ldquo;save game&amp;rdquo; feature for your code, allowing you to revert to previous versions, compare changes, and collaborate more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why Git? Git is a distributed version control system. This means that every developer has a full copy of the project history, allowing them to work offline and experiment freely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-git-concepts&#34;&gt;Key Git Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repositories (Repos): The main container for your project, including all the files and their history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commits: A snapshot of your changes at a specific point in time. Each commit has a message describing the changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Branches: A parallel line of development. Branches allow you to work on new features or bug fixes without affecting the main codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merging: Integrating changes from one branch into another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pull Requests (PRs): A way to propose changes to a project and have them reviewed by other developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-git-workflow&#34;&gt;Basic Git Workflow:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git clone: Download a copy of a repository to your local machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git add: Stage changes you want to include in your next commit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git commit: Save the staged changes with a descriptive message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git push: Upload your commits to a remote repository (e.g., GitHub, GitLab).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git pull: Download changes from a remote repository to your local machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;benefits-of-using-git&#34;&gt;Benefits of Using Git:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaboration: Makes it easy for multiple developers to work on the same project simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracking Changes: Provides a detailed history of all changes made to the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reverting to Previous Versions: Allows you to undo mistakes or revert to a working state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experimentation: Branches allow you to try out new ideas without risking the stability of the main codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backup: Your code is safely stored in a remote repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-learn-more&#34;&gt;Where to Learn More&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of great resources online for learning Git, including the official Git documentation, tutorials on YouTube, and interactive courses on platforms like Codecademy and Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control with Git is an indispensable tool for modern software development. Mastering Git will significantly improve your workflow and collaboration skills. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
